JUNIOR DEVOPS ENGINEER

Professional Summary

Seasoned DevOps Engineer with 16 years of IT experience resourcefully planning and deploying necessary application tools to meet organizational goals. Expert at generating quality coding to enhance critical software automation, accuracy, agility, and security based on the latest industry-standard concepts. Established history providing pivotal consultation with Dev, QA, security, and IT operations staff to influence software development effectiveness.

Work History

Accenture Contractor Jobs . Collegeville , PA Junior DevOps Engineer | 10/2018 - Current

- Managed service provider status containers: Kubernetes, Docker, Ansible, Automation: Linux: Build and maintained servers running Ubuntu, Amazon Linux, Centos, and Red Hat
- Maintained servers running Windows servers.
- AWS: creating and maintaining Auto scaling groups, IAM user roles, policies, EC2 Container Service (ECS), and Load Balancers.
- Configure AWS VPC with public and private subnets, configured Routing tables, Internet gateway, ACL's, Security groups.
- Performed Data migration across multiple Linux and Windows servers
- Created and Configured Red Hat, Ubuntu, CentOS, Solaris Virtual Machines in AWS using EC2, elastic, VPC, Subnets, Route Tables, NAT Gateway.
- Configured Cloud Watch and Nagios to monitor real-time granular metrics of all AWS Services and configured individual dashboards for each resource Agents
- Used GIT for source code version control and integrated with Jenkins for CI/CD pipeline, code quality tracking, and user management with build tools Maven.
- Deploying to AWS with Terraform and Ansible.

Amentum. Kings Point, NY Cybersecurity Analyst | 07/2013 - 10/2018

- Developed and maintained incident response protocols to mitigate damage and liability during security breaches.
- Designed company-wide policies to bring operations in line with Center for Internet Security (CIS) standards.
- Increased overall security posture of clients incorporating industry best practices and security frameworks.
- Network security analysis, monitoring incident response
- Detect and respond to security incidents Participate in security investigations
- Prepare cybersecurity briefings and reports
- Create end-of-shift reports to support teammates
- Monitoring and analyzing network traffic, Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS), security events and logs;
- Prioritizing and differentiating between potential intrusion attempts and false alarms. Develop, maintain, and follow SOC Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs).
- Support daily and monthly situation reporting per shift. Proactively reviewing large data sets for anomalous activity.
- Create detective content for monitoring devices such as IDS and SIEM and advise on proactive blocks for security architecture.
- Creating and tracking security investigations to resolution. Composing security alert notifications and other communications.
- Advising incident responders insteps to take to investigate and resolve computer security incidents. Staying up to date with current vulnerabilities, attacks, and countermeasures. This position requires ability to work shift schedule.
- Collaborated with client teams and resources to understand network dynamics, security toolset, and asset availability before building out
 custom-tailored monitoring and response plans to maximize value of investments while increasing security posture.
- Support daily and monthly situation reporting per shift.
- · Proactively reviewing large data sets for anomalous activity.
- And advise on proactive blocks for security architecture.
- Creating and tracking security investigations to resolution. Composing security alert notifications and other communications.

MTSonline . City , STATE Solution Center Engineer | 04/2006 - 07/2013

- Administered and maintained user community + workstations and servers in Solaris, HPUX, OS2, IRIX, LINUX, Free BSD, and Microsoft Windows environment.
- Performed OS/Hardware upgrades and patch installations on both UNIX and Windows servers and workstations.
- Installed and configured new RedHat/Windows servers and workstations.
- Performed script, kernel, and portioning changes as needed.
- Installed RPM packages to bring systems up to date or provide customized features. Installed updates using up2date. Resolved issues related to DNS configuration, NIS, or startup scripts. Added users and granted sudo privileges as required.
- Provided system technical support to external and internal users in installation, configuration, and administration of servers and workstations running on UNIX and Microsoft Windows operating systems.
- Tested and debugged user problems in internal lab to provide bug reports to system engineers in order to produce patches and enhancements to UNIX operating system.
- Investigated and resolved system software, hardware, and network issues as required
- Performed daily Novell and Active Directory administrative tasks including adding and deleting users, setting up shared areas, controlling data access, and managing print queues.

- AWS
- Azure
- OCI
- Python
- Bash Docker
- Kubernetes
- Ansible
- Terraform
- Jenkins
- Git
- Linux/Windows
- TCP/IP/Network Security
- Tomcat
- Nagois
- Apache
- Troubleshooting Skills
- Monitoring
- Continuous Integration

Education

Alhambra High School City 05/2000 High School Diploma Certifications

CompTIA: Security +

CompTIA Linux+